人类如何了解未知
How does one come to know The Unknowable?
人类需要什么技能
What faculties must a man possess?
自从人类发现鲸油
Since it was discovered that whale oil
可以以前所未有的方式点亮我们的城市
could light our cities in ways never achieved before,
全世界需求量暴涨
it created global demand.
使人类开始向
It had pushed man to venture further and further
海洋更深处冒险
into The Deep, Blue Unknown.
我们不知道海洋的深度
We know not its depths,
也不了解海洋里的生物
nor the host of creatures that live there.
怪物是否真的存在
Monsters, are they real?
或者这些故事只是让我们对海洋隐藏的秘密有所敬畏
Or do the stories exist only to make us respect the sea's dark secret?
楠塔基特岛 马萨诸塞州 1850年二月
这个问题使我即苦恼又兴奋
The question both vexes and excites me,
也是我再次向您写信请求一次会面的原因
and is the reason I've written you a second time to request a meeting.
一次和您交谈的机会 先生
A conversation with you, Sir,
我相信这会对我将要写的小说有很大帮助
I believe will serve me well for the novel I intend to write,
小说暂且名为 白鲸记
currently entitled Moby Dick
我期望您能考虑我的提议
I hope you will reconsider my offer.
未知 我的想象力始终想冒险的地方
The Unknown, that is where my imagination yearns to venture.
始终折磨我的问题是
And so, the question plagues me still:
人类如何才能探索未知
How does a man come to know The Unknowable?
此致 赫尔曼·梅尔维尔
Sincerely, Herman Melville.
我们打烊了
We're closed!
8点后不接客
No borders after eight o'clock.
你居然来了
You came.
亲爱的 有人来看你
There's someone here for you, My Love.
汤姆·尼克森
Tom Nickerson?
赫尔曼·梅尔维尔
Herman Melville.
我们收到了你的来信
We received your letter.
你要么走投无路要么是个傻子大老远跑来楠塔基特
You're either a desperate man or a fool to come all the way to Nantucket.
我的提议还在
Well, my offer still stands.
3个月的住宿换一晚的交谈
Three months'lodgings for a single night's talk.
这是我所有的钱了
It's all I have in the world.
但我更愿意看作是一次投资
But I'd prefer to think of it as an investment.
我想要你告诉我
I want you to tell me what happened...
埃塞克斯号发生了什么
to the Essex.
你觉得发生了什么
Well,what do you think happened?
有传言埃塞克斯号
There are rumblings,rumors that the Essex...
你想要什么 期望听到什么故事
What do you want?What story do you expect to hear?
白鲸的故事
That of The Whale.
埃塞克斯号搁浅了 有完整的报告
The Essex ran aground, there was a full inquiry.
我觉得那份报告不是事实全部
I believe the inquiry was less than truthful.
滚出去
Get out.
先生 你是埃塞克斯号上唯一的幸存者
You are the last survivor or the Essex, Sir.
如果你不说出来 谁还能讲出事实
If you won't talk, who will?
你没听见我的话吗 出去
You do not hear me, leave now.
你不能走 拜托 就一会儿  他没心情谈
- You mustn't go, please, just take a minute... - He's in no mind to talk, and
我不是大老远来就是为了被羞辱和浪费时间
I haven't come all this way to be humiliated and waste my time.
拜托了 梅尔维尔 先生
Please, Mr. Melville,
他从来不跟别人谈论埃塞克斯号 包括我 从不
he won't talk about the Essex to me, to anyone... never has... never.
我一点都不了解他
I don't know anything about him.
他的精神在受折磨 需要救赎
His soul is... in torment, and in need of confession.
拜托了 请让我和他谈 拜托了
Please, just let me talk to him... please.
亲爱的
Love,
我觉得和这个年轻人谈会对你有好处
I believe it would do you good to talk to the man.
不
No!
你听着
You listen well!
你酗酒要死的时候谁撑着这个家了
Who holds this place together while you drink yourself to death?
你必须和这个年轻人谈
You WILL talk with this man, as much as is necessary...
才能保住你的钱
to keep the money.
你知道我们的处境 汤姆
You know our circumstances, Tom.
我只说必要的
Only as much as is necessary.
我去拿威士忌
I'll get whiskey.
我忘了在信里提到我曾经是一名捕鲸手
I neglected to mention it in my letter, but I was a whaler once.
有过一次出航 新手
One trip. I mean... green hand.
那么你应该都经历过了
So, you've seen it all.
我妻子读过你的书
My wife read your books.
她很喜欢 很高兴听到
- She enjoyed them. - Happy to hear it.
销量很好 但我估计这个故事
They had good sales, but I think that THIS story
甚至能超过我销量不错的第一部小说
could surpass even the success of my first novel... which did quite well.
又一个你的航海轶事
Another of your seafaring yarns.
你听说过霍索恩吗 梅尔维尔先生
Have you read Hawthorne, Mr. Melville?
当下有一名作家 一个大作家
Now, there's a writer, a great writer.
他是的
He is.
但他不在这儿 因为我自己的原因
But he is not here, and I am...
我在这儿
for my own particular reasons.
我会告诉你埃塞克斯号 我相信你会失望的
I'll tell you of the Essex, I believe you will be disappointed,
但我说的每个字都是真实的
but every word I say will be true.
埃塞克斯号的故事就是两个男人的故事
The story of the Essex is the story of two men...
乔治·波拉德船长
Captain George Pollard,
和他大副 欧文·查斯
and his first mate, Owen Chase.
欧文 你不能迟到
Owen, you don't want to be late.
我会到那儿的 再说了 不能让我们的女儿睡在破陋的房子里对吧
I'll be there, besides, can't have our daughter sleeping under a leaky roof, can we?
你为什么那么肯定是女儿
What makes you so sure it's a girl?
肯定是的 她会提醒我你这么固执为什么我还是爱你
Well, it has to be, so she can remind me why I have to love you, and you being stubborn.
如果是女儿她会更像你而不是我
If it's to to be a daughter she'll be a version of you, not me.
金发而且一心想征服世界
Blond locks and determined to conquer the world.
我想过了今天你会用那件外套换一套制服
I suppose after today you'll be tradin' in that tunic for a uniform.
没错 终于能离开这破地方去赚个区艾瑟 船长该住的房子了
That's right, finally out of this patch of dirt for a captain's house in Quaise.
我不想住在周边都是古板的邻居的房子里
I don't need one of those houses in town with stuffy neighbors.
这里有足够供我们一家三口居住的地方
There's plenty room here for the three of us.
有时候你的温情真让人受不了
Ya know, sometimes your kind heart and good nature is just unbearable.
去做你的船长吧
Go get your captaincy.
- 你下注 1美元9分
- What's your bid? - One ninety.
我用2美元买到了一千加仑
I've got a thousand gallons at two dollars!
我占40份
I'll take 40 shares.
卖家 卖家 在这
Seller, seller, over here!
克雷斯拉回来了1600桶
Criterion's back with a fine haul, 1600 barrels.
伦敦市场新纪录 50磅银器换灯芯
A new record, 50 pounds Sterling for headmatter on the London market.
早上好 查斯先生
Good morning Mr. Chase.
马森先生 请进
- Mr. Mason. - Come in, please.
我的合伙人 本杰明·福勒
My partner, Benjamin Fuller.
早上好 先生 请坐
- Good morning, Sir. - Do sit down.
查斯先生 我们希望你知道我们对你
Mr. Chase, I do hope you realize how satisfied we are
为我们多年的工作有多么满意
with the work you've done for us over the years.
谢谢 先生
Oh, thank you, Sir.
我们其中一艘船 埃塞克斯号
And one of our ships, the Essex
已经花大价钱修整好准备出海了
has just be refitted at great expense and is to go to sea.
因为在她身上花了大价钱
Now, having made such an investment in her,
我们希望确保她在最适合的人手里
we want to be sure she's in the best possible hands.
所以
So...
我们很高兴邀请你成为这艘船的
it gives us great pleasure to offer you a position aboard her...
大副
as first mate.
大副 是的
- As first mate? - Uh-hum.
马森先生 你许诺过我上次出航带回来1500桶的话
Mr. Mason, you... you promised me command of a ship after my last voyage when
会让我当一艘船的船长 你保证过的
I brought you back 1500 barrels, do you remember? You gave me your word.
那个承诺要推迟了
That promise must now be deferred.
像别人一样我们最近行情不好
Like everyone else we've had a mean time recently.
我看不是
Well, never on my watch.
楠塔基特主宰了全球市场 这点不能变
Nantucket now dominates the world market, that must not change.
没有时间来试验
This is no time for experimentation.
埃塞克斯号必须由乔治·波拉德指挥
The Essex will be captained by George Pollard,
伟大的捕鲸家族的后裔
scion of a great whaling family.
他的父亲也是我们的老主顾
His father also happens to be our patron.
血统 查斯先生 你可以有出色的航海技能
Blood, Mr. Chase, you can have all the voyages under your belt you want
但血统还是更重要
but blood will always win out.
但是血统不会帮你的船装满油回来 马森先生
Yes, well, blood's not gonna fill the ship with oil, Mr. Mason.
要成功指挥船 船长需要被人尊重 如果别人不尊重他怎么办
To successfully command, a captain needs respect, now, what if the men don't respect him?
你就要确保别人尊重他
You will make sure that they do.
再见 先生们
Good day, Gentlemen.
我理解你的失落
I understand your disappointment.
所以
So...
115金币
A one-fifteenth lay.
我从来没有给新长官支付过这么多
And that's more than I've ever paid any first officer.
如果你带回来2000桶油 我向你保证
And if you bring back 2000 barrels of oil, I'll give you my word,
下次你就会是船长
next time you WILL have your captaincy.
你之前给过我保证来 马森先生
You've given me your word before, Mr. Mason.
这次我需要书面保证
So, this time I'll take it in writing.
波拉德船长 我们和查斯先生达成了协议
Captain Pollard, we've just had a most agreeable conversation with Mr. Chase,
他会很荣幸服务于您
who'd be honored to serve under you.
我很高兴听到
I'm glad to hear it.
现在我得照顾个没经验的
Now I'm to babysit a greenhorn.
一个含着他妈的金勺长大的船长了
Some cheerless Nantucket born with a damned silver spoon in his mouth.
我真应该当面拒绝
I should have thrown their offer back in their faces.
为什么 你已经拿到书面承诺了
Why? You now have the offer of command in writing.
骗子的世界什么都是假的 即使是书面承诺
Yes, well, a liar's word is worthless, even ON paper.
你知道即使你是商人我还是会爱上你的
You know I'd love you just as much if you were a merchant captain?
你不能离开两年之久
And you wouldn't be gone for two years.
我不会离开两年之久的
I won't be gone two years.
贝德福德家的捕鲸人上周回来了 离开了有三年
A Bedford whaler came back last week was gone three.
她失去了两个男人 而且惊魂落魄
She lost two men and still with her hull half empty.
他们是贝德福德家 没有我在
Well, they were from Bedford and they didn't have me aboard.
婊子养的
Son of a bitch!
我要指挥我自己的船
I will captain my own ship...
一艘捕鲸船
a whaling ship.
靠他们我们只能永远在这个鬼地方
Up to them all we'd ever have is a patch of dirt
我不会让这发生的 佩吉
and that's not going to happen, Peggy.
你父亲也是这么说的 你不能这么说
Those'd be your father's words, not yours.
他的话怎么了
What's wrong with his words?
他想要为家人为自己争取
He wanted things for his family, for himself.
他是个梦想家 欧文 是的 他是
- He was a dreamer, Owen - Yes, he was.
梦想大海 不带那些废物们出海
Dreamed of the sea and never got to sea with men like them.
至少他看到了他的孩子出生
At least he got to see his children born.
我只能干这些
It's all I know.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我嫁给了一个捕鲸人
I married a whaleman.
我会尽快回来 我发誓
I'll come back as quick as the sun is night, I swear.
一定要回来 向我保证
Please come back... promise me.
我已经向你发誓了 你还要我保证
I already swore to you, now you want me to promise, too.
我保证
I promise.
孩子 跟你说句话
Son, a word with you.
当船长 你不能当他们的朋友 你是他们的长官
To be a captain, you cannot be a friend, you are their superior.
别忘了这点 让别人记住这点
Never forget that, never let THEM forget that.
谢谢
Thank you, son.
你的曾祖父和其他人创立了这个行业
Your great-grandfather and a few others created this industry.
没有我们 没有你们 世界将会陷入黑暗
Without us, without you, the world plunges into darkness.
我希望能让家族名誉生辉 先生
I hope to bring honor to the Pollard family name, Sir.
啊 上帝创造了巨大的鲸 体长无比的神奇怪物
Thou didst, O Lord, create the mighty whale, That wondrous monster of a mighty length;
头硕身庞尾又阔 无边雄力人难度
Beyond conception his unmeasured strength.
恒古上帝宥永生 吾侪荏弱落凡尘
But, everlasting God, thou dost ordain that we, poor feeble mortals
妻儿一家须偷生
should engage ourselves, our wives and children to maintain,
赖此巨物维生存
This dreadful monster with a martial rage.
啊 上帝 用您的荣耀之光照亮这些男人
O Father, grant that your glorious light shine on these men,
保佑他们丰收的航程
and assure them a prosperous voyage,
保佑他们安全归来
that they may return SAFELY unto the womb ship.
楠塔基特的白鲸油
So that the white whales of Nantucket whale oil
可以继续照亮我们的房屋
may continue to keep light in our homes,
照亮我们的街道 为工业机器提供燃料
city streets safe from sin in the night, fuel the machines of industry,
推动我们伟大的国家前进
drive our great nation forward,
我们文明种族进步 我们祈祷
as our noble species evolves. In Your name, we pray.
现在是几月
So, what month is this?
年末了 我们是最后一批出海的船只了
Oh, late in the year, we were one of the last ships to go out.
也是为什么我和我朋友巴尔齐莱有卧铺
Which is why my friend Barzillai and I got a berth.
听着 我当时14岁
Look, I was fourteen... fourteen.
尼克森 别站着 干活
Nickerson, you're standin' around, boy! Move!
第一次出海 很害怕 更害怕显露出来
First time at sea, scared, more scared to show it.
巴尔齐莱当时17岁
Barzillai was seventeen.
在码头长大的孤儿都等不及被别人视作大人
Orphans, grew up on the wharf, both in a hurry to be called men.
你们慢腾腾干嘛 装船 快 快
What are you all guys waiting for? Get it aboard! C'mon! Haul away...!
他们戴的是饰针是什么
What are those pins they're wearing?
那些是白鲸徽章 汤姆斯
Those are whale pins, Thomas.
我怎么才能得到一个
How do I get one of them?
你得用长矛刺杀一头白鲸
Well, you've gotta thrust a killing lance.
那是世界上最大的怪物
The largest beast ever to breathe on the earth.
尼克森 把那绿色的东西给邦德先生
Nickerson, get the green stuff to Mr. Bond.
快点 妈的
Make it quick, damn it.
我总有一天会有一堆那东西
I shall have twelve of those one day.
把它们放到匣子里
Put 'em on the Grandira casket.
你也上船就说明一件事
Well, well, you being on board means only one thing.
是啊 这船上至少有一人明白欧文·查斯是谁
Yep! At least there's one person on this ship who knows the truth about Owen Chase.
不 可惜其他的船都已经满员了
No, but all the other ships have already crewed up.
不不 我洗心革面了 欧文 问题是你呢
No, no, I'm a reformed man, Owen, the question is are YOU?
别告诉我花花公子马修戒酒了
Don't tell me Matthew Joy has put down the bottle.
我有罪 欧文·查斯能消消他的坏脾气了吗
I have sinned. Has Owen Chase put down his temper?
平静的像教堂
Serene as the Church.
照我看来
I'll believe THAT when I see it.
考虑到我们的船长 我觉得你只能平静一小会儿
Given our captain I'll give your serenity about 48 hours.
祝你好运
Good luck.
波拉德 乔治·波拉德 欧文·查斯
- Pollard, George Pollard. - Owen Chase.
查斯 你父亲的名字对吗 对 是的
- Chase, your father's name, isn't it? - Yes, it is.
马上他要离开岛一段时间而我舒适得待在家
Very shortly he will be off island for some time and I'll be very much at home.
我要说 我有点意外 通常船长可以选择自己的大副
I say, I was surprised, normally a captain gets to choose his first mate.
如果是有经验的船长的话 是的
An experienced captain, yes.
当人 你可以理解老头的意思
Of course, you can understand from the owners' point of view,
他们想让自己的财产在适合的人手里
they wanted to put their investments in the hands of men.
确实
Indeed.
他们也许想要多些保障
They probably wanted a little extra reassurance, that's all.
看着点我 如果我做错什么了告诉我
Well, DO keep an eye on me, let me know if I'm doing anything wrong.
我不会迟疑的 船长
I'd have it not other way, Captain.
起锚
Shore up the anchor.
起风了 顶部横杆放下了吗 好
- Head's in the wind, is the top rail off? - Aye.
克拉德 掌舵 好
- Collard, Take the helm! - Aye!
花花公子 扬帆
Mr. Joy, make sail.
科尔 查普尔 守在起锚器旁
Mr. Cole, Mr. Chappel, stand by this anchor!
查普尔 掌舵
Mr. Chappel, take the helm!
为什么帆布还没有松开
Boyd! Why aren't those braces laid out?
打开帆 妈的
Set the sail, god damn it!
跑开
Heading to scram.
船长 注意头上 后面 船长
- Captain! Heads up! - Behind you head, Captain!
怎么了 谢泼德 帆布缠住了 长官
- What happened, Mr. Sheppard? - The jalousie felled the sheet, Sir.
帆布缠住了 查斯 他办不到
- The jalousie's jammed! - Chase, she still won't clear!
当心
Watch your step!
帆布 欧文
It's the jalousie, Owen!
走开
Stand clear!
干的漂亮 查斯
Nice piece of work, Mr. Chase!
如果两周内能到佛得角
If we make Cape Verdes in the next 2 weeks we'll
我们有很大几率能按时到太平洋
have a decent chance of reaching the Pacific on schedule.
玉米棒 查斯
Corn, Mr. Chase?
不需要 谢谢 从来不喜欢
No, thank you, Sir, never did have much of a taste for it.
太怪了
That's odd.
你爸在科德角是种玉米的吧 是的
- So, your father grew corn on Cape Cod. - That's right, he did.
你也猜到了 我那时天天吃这个吃腻了
As you can imagine, I suddenly grew tired of eating it every day.
种玉米 秋葵 大豆 然后他进了监狱
Corn, okra, beans, I believe? Before he went to jail.
花花公子 听起来熟悉吗
Are you familiar with this story, Mr. Joy?
你知道查斯是因为他的父亲进监狱才变成孤儿的吗
Were you aware that Mr. Chase was effectively orphaned due to his father's incarceration?
我们都有不同的经历
Well, we all have our paths to sea.
所以还是不要问太多问题为好
That's a motive to not ask too many questions.
一定不容易吧
Can't have been easy though, yet...
楠塔基特最伟大的航海家族收留你
You had Nantucket's great seafaring family to adopt you.
很久没有楠塔基特人称呼我陆人
This is far from the first time I've been called a landsman...
或者提醒我不是他们一家人了
or off-islander by some Nantucket reminding me how I am NOT part of their family.
请允许我 船长 我要去分配捕鲸船和值班了
Now, if the captain will excuse me, there are whale boats and watches to assign.
不 船长 滴酒不沾
- No, Sir, not for me. - Not a drop?
不 船长 就像我说的 有时候少问问题更好
No, Sir, like I said, sometimes the fewer questions one asks, the better.
花花公子 这有个漂亮姑娘
That's a gorgeous girl, Mr. Joy.
远东的鲸骨上刻的
Region of move me that, carved from a Far East whalebone.
不许碰
No touching!
我一直以为你已经结婚了
I always thought you were married anyway.
是的 但看她
I am, and there she is.
这是她的鼻子
Well, that's her nose anyway.
恭喜 女士们
Congratulations, ladies.
今天启航干的不错
That was a fine job trimin' sails today.
我从来没有过这么一群捕鲸人
A sorrier pack of deck-whalers I don't think I've ever seen.
查普尔 长官
- Mr. Chappel. - Sir.
船长鱼叉手
Captain's harpooner.
劳伦斯 你做我的 遵命 长官
- Mr. Lawrence, you'll be mine. - Aye, Sir.
彼得森 二副的鱼叉手
And Mr. Peterson, second mate's harpooner.
遵命 长官
Aye, Sir.
一船上六人 首要一点要警觉
There'll be six men to a boat, first rules in the row, six bells sharp.
我们还没到哈利法克斯以东 长官
We're not even east of Halifax, Sir.
你叫什么 克芬 亨利·克芬
- What's your name? - Coffin, Henry Coffin.
他是船长的表弟 长官
He's the Captain's cousin, Sir.
克芬先生 你觉得一头白鲸会知道自己在哈利法克斯以东吗
Well, well, Mr. Coffin, do you think a whale knows it's east of Halifax?
我不知道你们原来是谁 或者怎么来的
I don't know who all of you are, or how you got here,
你们中一些人可能甚至是重犯 在隐藏或者逃亡
Some of you probably have felonies, or are hidin' or on the run.
没关系 我不关心 我对你们的要求只有一个
That's fine, I don't give a damn, but we interred you for just one thing...
只有一个 就是鲸油
and one thing only, and that is whale oil.
我要装满2000桶油并尽快回家
I intend to fill our 2000 barrels and be home as quickly as possible.
即使天气好而且没有鲸出没 克芬先生
And even when the weather is fine and there ARE no whales, Mr. Coffin,
我们会放下船练习如何捕鲸
we will lower the boats and practice all maneuvers necessary in a capture of a whale.
谁要是想偷懒就自己游回家 明白吗
And any man who is idle will find himself swimmin' to home. Is that understood?
明白 长官
- Aye, sir. Aye, Sir. - Aye, Sir.
小子 上甲板
Green horn, on deck!
走
On ya go!
遵命 遵命 陆人
Aye, aye, landsman.
汤姆·尼克森 对吧 是的 长官
- Thomas Nickerson, right? - Aye, Sir.
有些人一开始会觉得恶心
Ya know, some feel sick at first.
拉我上去 这是最好的办法
- Pull me back up! - Best way to square up to King Neptune, Boy.
求你了 拉我上去
Please, bring me up.
好点了吗
Better now?
长官 非常对不起
Sir, I am so sorry.
你现在有故事写信回家告诉你母亲了
Well, now you got something to write home to your mother about.
我母亲葬在史密斯山
My mother's buried up in Smith's Hill,
我爸也是 他
and a stone for my father, too, he was...
他在我出生前就葬身大海了
he was lost at sea before I was born.
给我
Here, give me that.
白鲸现在是你的家人了 是好是坏
The whale's is your family now, Boy, for better or for worse.
坏处多是
For worse mostly.
清理甲板 小子
Swab the deck, Kid!
你离学会捕鲸和航行还差远了
You're a long way from base to be whaling and sailing.
是 长官
Aye, aye, Captain.
你系错绳子了 是 长官
- You got that line wrong, Nickerson. - Aye, Captain.
如果有必要我们会训练到日落
We'll stay at this until sunlight if we have to.
是 长官
Aye, Captain.
鱼叉手准备乘船
Harpooners make ready to boat.
雷 动作快点 我的错
- Need to move quicker, Mr. Ray! - My mistake.
没有女人玩了 查斯
Ain't no more wee whores, Mr. Chase.
你现在是水手了 哈哈
You're a sailor, now! Yeah!.
干的不错 雷
Not bad, Mr. Ray, well done!
要习惯 伙计们 你们得像马一样工作
Get used to it, mates, you gotta work like horses.
查斯先生 长官
- Mr. Chase. - Sir.
扬帆
Set stuns'ls.
这样做好吗 长官 我们接近洋流
Is that wise, Sir, we're near the Gulf Stream.
看这天气也还得缓慢前进
Best to be five knots fto even see the weather.
我们落后两天行程了
We are two days behind.
你得在东风来临前弥补上时间
You need to make up the time before we catch the east wind.
扬帆
Set stuns'ls.
拴绳 扬帆
Belay that, set stuns'ls.
克芬 松开帆 船长要提速
Get her off, Mr. Coffin, the Captain wants speed!
遵命 长官
Aye, Sir.
她老了 但是还能让我们爽 哈哈
She might be old but she can still blow, boys!
长官 右舷方向有一飓风团 我们需要马上降帆
Sir, a squall on the starboard route, we need to shorten the sail immediately.
还不行 查斯
Not just yet, Mr. Chase.
长官 我们以8里的速度驶向风暴
Sir, we are headed into a storm of more than 8 knots
而且速度越来越快
and it's movin' faster than that.
让它来吧 水手们在陆地上呆久变软弱了
Let it come, the men are soft from months on land, they
他们需要一次洗礼 告诉他们工作开始了
need a good baptism, let them know our work has begun.
如果我们不降帆并驶离 风暴一定会追上我们的
If we don't shorten sail and bear off it'll catch us on the beam.
查斯 我们继续向前航行
Chase, we will stand on.
劳伦斯 继续向前 继续向前 长官
- Mr. Lawrence, hold our course. - Holding course, Sir.
我们这样前行会追到只差半天的航程
We'll lose half a day running like that.
我们最后能赶上 如果我们的人
We'll scut the end of it, if the men can't
不能应付这样的狂风 上帝也帮不了我们
handle a gust like this, then God help us all.
固定好一切应付糟糕的天气
Best secure for heavy weather.
准备好应付天气 邦德 我们要驶向风暴了
Best prepare for weather, Mr. Bond, we're headed into a squall.
我们必须降帆离开这里 退下 查斯先生
- We must fall off and run with it. - Stand down, Mr. Chase.
劳伦斯 航向不变 航向不变 长官
- Mr. Lawrence, hold your course. - Holding course, Sir.
降帆 查斯
Shorten the sails, Mr. Chase.
我们要砍下那些帆
We need to cut those sails down!
船掉头 向陆地开
Turn the ship, head for land!
不 损坏已经造成了
No, the damage is done!
太晚了 太他妈晚了
It's too late, it's too god damned late!
我们会撞上的
We'll be broadsided!
抓牢
Hold on!
小心
Look out!
花花公子
Mr. Joy!
我们要割断 我知道了 欧文
- We have to cut away the... - I've got it, Owen!
我们要让船摆正
We have to set her up right!
你说要见我 长官
You wish to see me, Sir.
明天六时 你召集船员
At six bells tomorrow, you will assemble the crew,
告知他们我们将返回楠塔基特维修
inform them that we will be returning to Nantucket for repairs.
然后你向他们道歉你干涉了船长的命令
You will then apologize to them for interfering with a captain's order
今天差点让船上的每个人都为此丧命
which nearly cost the lives of every man on this ship today.
什么
What?
返回到港口我会接受你的辞呈
I'll accept your resignation upon our return to port.
就这些
That will be all.
是你下命令杨帆的 长官
It was your order to set stuns'ls, Sir.
命令没问题 这些人需要锻炼
That decision was sound, the men needed testing.
你送他们进风暴
- You sent 'em into a storm? - That...
那是幸运不好
was unlucky.
不 这是缺乏航海经验 责怪运气只会显得软弱
No, it was bad seamanship, and blaming misfortune is just plain weakness.
你他妈的无礼 你知道你在和谁说话吗
Damn your impertinence! Do you know who you're speaking to?
我是船长乔治·波拉德 波拉德
My name is CAPTAIN George Pollard. POLLARD!
而你查斯先生 无论你衣袖上钉多少白鲸徽章
And you Mr. Chase, no matter how many whale pins you may have on your lapel,
你不过是个农民的儿子
are nothing more than the son of a farmer,
仗势欺人才当上的长官
who's managed to bullying his way into an officer's tunic.
滚出去
Now, get out!
不带一桶油回港口是个错误 长官
To return to port without a single barrel of oil would be a mistake, Sir.
和名字是波拉德或者查斯没什么关系
And not behoove a man whose name is Pollard... or Chase, for that matter.
对我们来说最好是抓紧时间工作
And the best thing for both of us would be t'work all hours God sends us.
把船装满油一年之内回到家
Fill this ship with oil, and be home inside a year
然后各自分道扬镳
and rid of one another as quickly as possible.
相信我 我也迫不及待这样做
Trust me, I have never been as desirous of that as you.
当然 这由船长来做决定
Of course, that is the Captain's decision.
他们像一对新婚夫妇
They were like a new married couple.
新婚夫妇能容忍对方 梅尔维尔先生
A new married couple tolerate each other, Mr. Melville,
但新婚夫妇也能两败俱伤
but a new married couple can also bring down a ship.
你结婚了吗 梅尔维尔先生 是的
- You married, Mr. Melville? - I am.
上帝仁慈
The Lord have mercy on ya.
第一个孩子也快生了
First child on the way, too.
那你的妻子知道你把所有的积蓄都带来了
So, does your good wife know that you brought all you have in the world here tonight,
并且给了一个陌生人吗
and givin' it to a stranger?
不知道 先生 你总让人吃惊
- No, Sir. - You're full of surprises, aren't you?
那么 埃塞克斯号没有回港口
So... the Essex did not return to port.
没有 她继续驶向大海
- She did not. - She continued out to sea.
是的 但不久 我们都听到这个捕鲸人都盼望听到的吼声
Yes, she did, but before long, we heard the call this all whale men pray for...
Ho!
喷水
Blows!
是大家伙 喷水了
A big one! Thar she blows!
公的母的 拉姆斯德尔先生  他们是公的
- White or sperm, Mr. Ramsdell? - Sperm whales they are!
查斯先生  升起船只
Mr. Chase, hoist and swing boat.
都来甲板
- All Hands! All hands on deck! - All hands on deck!
放船
Lower away!
出海三个月 南大西洋
再加把劲儿
Come on, put your back into it.!
幼年鲸
There's the calf.
幼年鲸 母鲸
- That's the calf? - That's the cow!
乖乖 那是我们的钱
That's our boy! That's the money!
尼克森 使劲
Nickerson! Push!
够四十桶油了吧 五十桶
- Forty barrels there? - Fifty!
天 他是个大家伙
Boy, he's a buster!
使劲划 要不然他要逃了
Take the oars, lads! Quick or he'll god damn run!
划起来 机灵点 伙计们 机灵点
Pull those oars up! Smartly, lads, smartly!
小心桨端
Mind your oars!
拉姆斯德尔 准备绳 是 长官
- Mr. Ramsdell, prepare the line. - Aye, Sir.
第一头是我的
The first one's mine.
瞄准她的弱点
Aim her to the free spot!
拉 拉 跟着
Pull! Pull! Stay on him.
伙计们 你们坐上了楠塔基特号第一班雪橇
You're on your first Nantucket sleigh ride, Boys.
地球上最可怕的生物
The most fearsome creature to ever live on this earth.
我的手
My hand!
你得把绳弄湿 尼克森
You need to wet the line, Nickerson.
只剩140英寻的绳子了 查斯先生
A hundred forty fathoms' of line left, Mr. Chase.
只剩80英寻的绳子了 长官
Eighty fathoms' of line left, Sir.
他会把我们拖到水里的
He's gonna pull us under!
马修 我要你的绳子 给我绳
- Matthew, I need your line! - Feed the line!
彼得森给我绳子 是的 长官
- Peterson give me the line! - Aye, Sir.
把那绳给我 彼得森 我们只剩60英寻的绳子了 长官
- Give me that line, Mr. Peterson. - We're down to 60 fathoms' of line left, Sir.
20英寻了 查斯先生 松开绳
- Twenty fathoms, Mr. Chase! - Tie it off!
快
Go!
彼得森 你来 是 长官
- Peterson, lay on! - Aye, Sir.
还剩多长的绳子
How many fathoms can he draw?
不 不 等等
No, no, no, wait!
欧文 不 不是现在
- Owen! - Oh, no, not yet!
别碰那绳 只剩50英寻了 长官
- Don't touch that line. - Down to 50 fathoms, Sir.
欧文 他妈的 我说了不要动
- Owen! God damn it! - I said don't touch it!
剩30英寻了 花花公子
Thirty fathoms left, Mr. Joy.
剩10英寻了 长官
Ten fathoms left, Sir!
真是漫长的过程
It's been a long drive.
油中的脂肪
Blubber in the oil.
它们要吃掉你的钱了
They're gonna eat your money.
滚开 混账畜生
Get out of there, you sons of bitches!
- 你拿到了吗 拿到了 查斯
- You got it? - Got it, Chase.
看起来怎么样 不怎么样
- How's it lookin'? - Not good.
就这么多了
That's it.
查斯先生 什么
- Mr. Chase, Sir? - Yep.
长官 就这么多了 我们拿不到更多了
That's all of it, Sir, we can't get anymore out.
那就是金矿 伙计们 继续挖
That's the gold in there, Boys, c'mon, keep diggin'.
我块头太大下不去 得找个身材小的
- I'm too big to really go down there. - Then find someone who can.
尼克森 过来小子
Nickerson, come here boy!
嘿 我喊你过来
Hey! I said c'mere!
爬进去
Climb on in with 'im.
来啊 汤姆斯
Come on, Thomas.
这里面的东西可比它的肉值钱多了
What's in there is worth a HELLEVA lot more than what they're boilin' down.
长官 我不行 对不起 我做不了
Sir, I can't, I'm sorry. I can't.
你自己进去或者我让你睡在里面
You get down there, or I'll have you sleep down there.
你用牙齿把这东西咬住 小子
You best put that between your teeth, Boy.
它里面臭得很
It tastes worse than the Devil's asshole down there.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉 尼克森 我的枕头送你
- Sorry. - Here, Nickerson, take my pillow with ya!
下去
Down ya go.
一个人在里面能更了解自己
A man gets to know himself down there.
他们有送你进一头鲸的头里面吗 没有 他们饶了我
- Did they ever send you into a whale's head? - No, I was spared.
那里面才是宝藏所在
Well, that's where the treasure is.
我永远都不会忘记那第一头
I'll never forget that first bull.
47桶油 当然 幸福很短暂
Forty-seven barrels... of course, the happiness was short lived.
那片水域没有鲸鱼可捕了
The waters had all been fished out?
是的 所以我们向更远处前进
That they had. So, we headed further out.
在那一个月之后
It was a month around the Horn.
离开了南大西洋
Left the South Atlantic behind with a sliver of hope
期望情况会变好
that things would change for the better.
但到了太平洋事实上没有改善
But making the Pacific didn't improve our lot.
太他妈难看到鲸了
Whale sightings were TOO damn scarce.
将近一年后脾气冲动的船长
After nearly a year at sea the temperaments of our captain.
和大副都变的沮丧
And our first mate grew more strained.
船长波拉德几乎整天待在船舱里
Captain Pollard spent most days and nights in his cabin,
害怕看到船员无法交代
afraid to look his crew in the eye.
我们的仓储大半还空着
Our hold was almost empty.
凝视着我们皮毛的成果只会提醒我们
To gaze upon our paltry efforts only served as a reminder
离回家还有很长一段路
that we were a long way from going home.
阿塔卡梅斯 厄瓜多尔
我听不懂 说英语
I don't talk that talk. Speak English?
他们在说鲸油
They're talking whale oil.
牧师坚持要我们写信回家告知我们的情况
他觉得这些信帮得了谁
那些寡妇
船都没有的船主
你还要像这样生活多久 船长
写信给西班牙 为你和你的船长 祈求原谅
没人可以阻止发生的一切
谁会相信呢 没有人 顾主不会相信的
这么多年你用油换来钱装满他们的口袋
长官
Capitбn.
打扰了 当地人告诉我你的航程遇到阻碍了 长官
Excuse me, the locals told me that your voyage was waylaid, Sir.
埃塞克斯号船长 乔治·波拉德
Captain George Pollard, the Essex.
圣玛丽亚号船长 克莱门特佩莱斯
Capitбn Clemente Pelaez, the Santa Maria.
给大伙来一杯
Would you buy a colleague a drink?
老样子 乔治 是的 船长
- Same as always, George. - Yes, Captain
坏运气
Bad luck, huh?
那有多远
How far out?
远到只有傻子才会去
Far enough for only a fool to go.
那是多远
How far would that be?
一千里格 在赤道附近
A thousand leagues along the Equator...
近海区域
in offshore grounds.
鲸都在那儿
Were there whales there?
多到你做梦不敢想
More than you've ever dreamt.
成百上千 密密麻麻望不到边
Hundreds... fields of flukes as far as the eye can see.
他们原本一天就够装满3000桶油
They could fill up 3000 barrels in the space of a day.
什么意思 "原本"
What do you mean, "Could have"?
要不是那里的那头怪物
If it weren't for that demon...
一头鲸
a whale.
白如蜡石
White as alabaster,
一百英尺长
a hundred feet long,
我的六名船员因为它丧命
sent six of my crew to their graves,
剩下的我们 只会让人想起那头怪物
and the rest of us, something to remember him by.
那头白鲸 他跳舞给你看 还逗你玩吗
Now, this white whale, did he dance a jig and pick your pocket, as well?
谢谢
Thank you.
你相信他的鬼话
Do you believe that?
我们马上出发 赶上南风带
We set sail now, catch the south easterlies,
这是我们绝佳的机会 填饱肚子 我们有机会在半年内回家
this is by our best time, fill our belly, we can be home in six months.
你怎么看 查斯先生
What say you, Mr. Chase?
没必要再忍受这种困境了
No need to endure our predicament for a moment longer than necessary.
同意
Amen to that.
Amen.
贪婪影响了船长和大副
Greed took hold of our Captain and the first mate.
然后我们沿着赤道前往一千里格外的
So, we headed out... a thousand leagues along the Equator...
但是没想到 传言流开了
but with no agenda, speculation began.
说鲸都藏在那里
This is where the whales are gonna hide.
那是我们能到达的最远的地方
It was as far from land as we could possibly go.
但是我们要追捕他们
But we hunted them down.
几个世纪前 水手们害怕会航到地球边界
Centuries before, sailors feared sailing off the edge of the earth,
但我们是驶向理智的边缘
but we were headed for the edge of sanity.
信任给猜疑让位
Trust gave way to doubt...
期望消除迷信
hope to blind superstition.
船长 船员在议论
Cap'n, the men are talking.
这很正常
That's what men do.
他们对你航行这么远的决定不满
They aren't happy with your decision to sail out this far.
你纠正他们的观点了吗
Well, did you correct them?
你提醒他们我们的目标是用鲸油装满这艘船
Did you remind them of our purpose to fill this ship with whale oil
如果那里有成百上千头鲸 为什么不去呢
and if the whales ARE a thousand leagues out, then that is where we go?
表哥 拜托了 这太疯狂了
Cousin, please, this is madness.
你被那人影响了
You have let yourself be influenced by that man.
你必须把船调头
You must turn this ship back.
我建议你回去 消除他们的疑虑
I suggest you go back down, reassure the men, the leader,
以后别再仗着家庭身份来找我
and don't ever, ever abuse the privilege of family with me again...
克芬先生
Mr. Coffin.
出海第十四个月
怎么了
What is it?
听 查斯先生
- Listen... - Mr. Chase.
我看到些白柱 哪里
- I see some white water. - Where?
左舷
Port side!
你看到什么了吗
You see anything?
出船 出船
- Lower away! - Lower away!
那头挂物要完蛋了
The Devil'll take the Mexican ground.
用力刺他 刺他
Stick him hard! Stick him!
一直向前 彼得森
Straight ahead, Peterson.
别人他咬了船桨 伙计们
Don't let him chew the oars, Boys.
看着点
Back to it!
那头鲸 是的
- The whale? - Yes.
传言是真的 是的
- So, it's true. - Yes.
可惜是真的
Too much is true.
全速
Full pressure!
邦德先生 后退4码 载具放下来
Mr. Bond, back to 4 yards, lower the tackle!
遵命 长官
Aye, Sir.
劳伦斯先生 驶向下风口的鲸群
Mr. Lawrence, take us leeward headed straight for the school.
马上 长官
Right, Sir.
热焦油 长官 我们会找到他的
- Hot tar, Sir. - We'll find him.
我们接近背部了
We're close to black skin.
靠近她
Sneak up on her!
她是我们的了
She's ours, Lads.
那是什么 劳伦斯先生
What was that, Mr. Lawrence?
查斯先生
Mr. Chase.
妈的
God damn it.
找劳伦斯过来
Find Mr. Lawrence...
找劳伦斯去抽水
Get Mr. Lawrence to man the pumps!
他在哪儿
Where is he?
左舷船头
Port bow!
给我最大的鱼叉
Get me the biggest tines we have.
他想来一战
He wants a fight.
我从来没过鲸这么做 劳伦斯 掌舵
- I never seen a whale do that. - Mr. Lawrence, take the wheel.
拉姆斯德尔 把绳子另一头系在前桅
Mr. Ramsdell, secure the other end of the line to the foremast.
遵命 长官
Aye, Sir.
只要我还活着 他是我的
As I live and breathe, he's mine.
当心
Look out!
船长
Cap'n...
埃塞克斯号 它在倾斜
The Essex, it's listing.
帮我调头
Help me turn around.
勇敢点 在这 过来 尼克森
- That's it, be brave. - Here! Full ahead, Mr. Nickerson.
查斯先生
Mr. Chase.
一头鲸撞坏了船
A whale threw her, it stove the ship.
什么
What?
我们失去了伊斯顿和山本
We lost Easton and Sanborn.
水泵没用了 长官
The pumps are useless, Sir.
准备弃船 我们不能划着回去
- Prepare to abandon ship. - We can't row away home!
我们必须从船上带走必要的东西
We have to strip from the sails and jimmy-rig something.
遵命 长官
Aye, Sir.
带上尽可能多的水和食物
Get as much food and water as you can carry.
我们需要你们能找到的任何一滴水
We're gonna need all the fresh water you can find.
我们尽可能待在一块
We stick together as much as we can.
查普尔先生 储备物
Mr. Chappel, the provisions!
带上尽可能多的食物
Take as much food as you can carry.
清理道路
Make way!
拿住 储备食物
- Got it? - Hard tack and stock!
带上那些蜡烛 船帆下来了
- Grab the candles there! - Lower away!
拿上那些储物柜
Take those tack lockers.
拉上去
Pull her up!
快 尼克森
Come on, Nickerson!
当心
Pace yourself!
抓住手 我拉到你了 拉他上来
- Grab the hand! I got you! - Get 'im up!
离油远点
Gotta get away from the oil.
尼克森 查斯先生在哪儿 他刚才还在这 长官
- Nickerson! Where is Mr. Chase? - He was just here, Sir.
查斯先生
Mr. Chase!
查斯
Mr. Chase, Sir!
大副在哪儿 离远点
- Where is the first mate? - Away!
查斯
Mr. Chase, Sir!
他在那儿 他在那儿 他在那儿
There he is! There he is! There he is!
这里 查斯在那儿
- Over there! - There's Mr. Chase!
查斯先生
Mr. Chase!
抓住他了
We got him.
我们去钓鱼是吧
Goin' fishin', are we?
都准备好了 花花公子
Clear and loaded, Mr. Joy.
退后 不然我们会和她一起下沉的
Back away, or she'll take us down with her.
南美洲以西 2000海里
船长 我们的食物怎么办
Captain, what about our provisions?
每人每天两盎司的硬面饼
Two ounces of hardtack a day per man...
和半杯水
and half a cup of water.
不够的
We can't live on that.
是他
It's he!
对 是他
Yeah, it's him all right.
你骗不了我 查斯先生
You don't fool me, Mr. Chase.
克芬先生 是吗
- Mr. Coffin. - That right?
你带我们来这的 你知道的
You put us here, you know you put us here.
嘿 放下枪 放下手枪
- Hey! Put it down. - Put the pistol down!
告诉我你害怕了
Say you're scared!
克芬先生 放下枪
Mr. Coffin, put the pistol down!
你清楚食物和水耗尽后会怎样
You know what happens when the food and water runs out!
按船长说的做 克芬先生
Do as the Captain says, Coffin!
我只是想看到
I just want to see
陆人害怕 克芬 放下枪
- the landsman scared. - Coffin, put the pistol down!
这是命令 按照船长说的做
- That's an order! - Do as the Captain says! Now!
说啊 亨利
- Say it! - Henry.
说啊 说啊
Say it! Say it!
亨利 放下枪
Henry! Put the pistol down.
Henry, put it down.
然后向东
So, east it was,
按来的路线回去
back in the direction we'd come,
顶着烈日靠着一个指南针
With only the sun and a compass.
所有的方向都看起来一样
All directions looked the same.
我们的期望是靠着西风带漂到复活岛
Our hope was to catch the westerlies to Easter Island,
3000英里的距离
a journey of 3,000 miles.
过了12天我们漂到了南方
For 12 days we've drifted south.
6度纬度
Six degrees latitude.
离复活岛差了十万八千里
Not one mile closer to Easter Island.
我们被诅咒了
We are cursed.
当我们赶上风带我们会弥补上的
We'll make up for it when we catch the variables.
我们会赶上的
We'll catch 'em.
抓牢了 船长
Hold on, Captain!
花花公子 帆绳缠住了
Mr. Joy, the halyard's jammed.
花花公子 抓住它 花花公子
Mr. Joy! Grab at it, Mr. Joy!
马修
Matthew!
马修 发生了什么 发生了什么
Matthew, okay, what happened? What happened?
你在这干什么 让我看看
- What are you doing here? - Let me take a look.
不 不 不 让我看看
- No, no, no. - Let me take a look.
我没事 我没事
I'm fine, I'm fine.
放松 我知道 让我看一眼
Just relax, I know, I know, let me take a look.
我被击中头部了 我没事 好吗
I'm hit on the head, it's good, right?
给他些水 我不需要什么水
- Give him some water! - I don't need any water!
给他他妈的一些水喝
Give him some God damned water.
不 不 我不需要水 我没事
No, no, no, I don't need water, I'm fine.
拿着
Take that, take it!
没事
I gotcha, I gotcha!
没事的 你会没事的
All right, you'll be all right.
嘿 你们在看什么 我没事
Hey, what are you all looking at, I'm fine.
波拉德船长 我装的
Cap'n Pollard, this is fiddle.
我忽悠你们的 听见了吗
This is God damn fiddle, ya hear me?
欧文 在
- Owen. - Yeah.
我没事 我没事
I'm fine, all right, I'm fine.
我没事 离开这
- Thank you. - I'm fine! Get out of here!
他没事
He is good.
我们走
Let's go.
为什么在死人身上浪费水
Why waste water on a dead man?
他们从小一起航海 情同手足
Fancy men who know each other, sailed together since childhood.
你告诉我
Now, tell me,
你会坐等着看你的兄弟死去吗
could you just sit there and watch your own brother die?
简单的算术问题 查普尔先生
It's simply a matter of numbers, Mr. Chappel.
水不够我们所有人用
There's not enough for all of us.
为什么在死人身上浪费水
Why waste water on a dead man?
为什么浪费水
Why waste water...
Why waste water?
为什么在死人身上浪费水
Why waste water on a dead man?
尼克森先生
Mr. Nickerson?
为什么在死人身上浪费水 你还好吗 先生
- Why waste water on a dead man? - Are you all right, Sir.
我不能 不能什么
- I cannot. - Cannot what?
不 你 你 你知道足够多了 你了解够多了
No, you... you... you have enough, you have more than enough.
但是 先生 我们都讲到这儿了
But, Sir! We've come so far.
我们必须善始善终 我们有约定的 先生
- We have come to an end. - We have an agreement, Sir.
拿着钱离开 这是魔鬼的交易
Take the money and leave! You've a devil's bargain!
不 长官 魔鬼喜欢隐藏秘密
No, Sir, the devil loves his unspoken secrets...
特别是那些蚕食人的灵魂的秘密
especially those that fester in a man's soul.
你的秘密是什么
What's yours?
我不是一个好作家
I'm not a great writer.
我不是霍索恩
I'm not Hawthorne.
从我学写作以来
After my first hearing of Odysseus,
这个故事一直困扰着我
this tale has haunted me.
它消耗着我
It consumes me.
我害怕如果我不写这个故事
I fear if I do not write it,
我会再也没办法写作
I should never write again.
还有什么
What else?
我害怕如果我写这个故事
I fear if I DO write it,
写出来的不如故事精彩
that it will not be as good as it should be.
继续讲这个故事 先生
Continue the story, Sir...
为了彼此
for the both of us.
困住的第34天
传过去
Pass that down.
给
Here.
我们感谢你 主 赐予我们的食物
We thank thee, Lord, for this is our food...
赐予我们的光 健康 和所有美好的东西
for light, good health, with every good.
那里
There.
陆地
Land!
陆地 欧文 陆地
Land, Owen! Land!
陆地 陆地 陆地
Land! Land! Land!
划船 快
Row! Get 'way! Get 'way!
划船
Row!
停下 停下 停下
Hold fast! Hold fast! Hold fast!
查斯 什么东西 长官
Mr.Chase, what is it, Sir?
查斯 那是什么怪物 你怎么停下了
Mr. Chase, what the devil is it, why have you stopped?
他一直在跟着我们 什么
- He's been following us. - What?
那里什么都没有 查斯先生
There's nothin' out there, Mr. Chase.
那里什么都没有 长官
There ain't nothin' out there, Sir.
长官 你在干什么
Sir, what are you doing?
他在哪儿
Where is he?
这可能是迪西岛
It could be Ducie Island.
没有地图 指南针 象限仪 没办法确认
Without a map, compass or quadrant there's no way to be certain.
我们昼夜都亮着火
We will keep fires going night and day,
但愿过往的船只注意到我们的浓烟
hope a passing ship catches sight of our smoke.
这是我想让你们看的
This is what I wanted you to see.
他们肯定在这很长时间了
They've been here a long time, for no doubt...
一定也在等船只
waiting for a ship.
但是没有船来过
But no ship came.
没有船会来
No ship is going to come.
如果我们呆在这 我们会死
If we stay, we die.
你们觉得如果鸟儿过来看到
How long do you think it would take to trust the birds
自己的蛋被吃了会多久不再过来
to stop coming here once they see their eggs eaten?
这是知道自己将要死去的好处
It's a privilege to know the moment of one's death in advance.
可以为此准备
And to be able to prepare for it...
离家太远的诅咒
a curse to be so far from home...
或者有机会说再见但没机会和解
or a chance to say goodbyes, without a chance to make peace...
或者报仇的机会
or a chance to settle scores.
但是 我们之间清楚了
But alas, at least those are settled between us,
船长
Cap'n?
什么船长
Captain of what?
埃塞克斯号沉没了不是你的责任
The Essex was lost and no fault o'yours.
我该受谴责 你不是船长
- I was as much to blame... - You were not the Captain!
你天生就是干这活的料
You were born to do this job.
我只是生下来只能干这个
I was just born into it.
我们干了什么 你觉得 乔治
What we do, do ya think, George?
我们干了什么冒犯了上帝 让他这么不开心
What offense did we give God to upset him so?
冒犯上帝的是那些白鲸
The only creature to have offended God here is the whale.
不是我们
Not us?
不是我们的傲慢 我们的贪婪 看我们现在在哪儿
Not our arrogance, our greed? Look where we find ourselves.
我们是上帝按自己喜好创造出来的高级生物
We are supreme creatures made in God's own likeness.
我们是地球上的主宰
We're earthly kings,
我们要环航我们居住的星球
whose business it is to circumnavigate the planet bestowed to us.
将自然屈服于我们的意志
And to bend nature to OUR will.
我们经历了这么多你还觉得主宰一切吗
You really feel like an earthly king after everything that we've been through?
我们什么都不是 我们是微粒 灰尘 但是我们
- We're nothing... we're specks... dust. - But we're...
拂晓时朝太阳方向行驶
We sail into the sun at dawn.
如果我们要死 死在上帝的光辉里
If we are to die, with God's grace.
让我们像男人一样死去
Let us die as men.
我们准备好了吗 维克斯先生 是的 长官
- Are we ready, Mr. Weeks? - Aye, Sir.
查普尔先生
Mr. Chappel.
莱特先生 我不能 长官
- Mr. Wright. - I can't do it, Sir.
我 洛克斯 维克斯
Me, Locks and Weeks...
我们留下来
we're stayin'.
准备出发 马修
Ready to go, Matthew?
我来帮你一把 有什么用
- I'll give you a hand here... - What's the point?
你听见我说的吗 不 我们一起回家 一起回家
- You hear me? - No, we're goin' home, we're goin' home.
没用的
There's no point.
走吧
Just go.
妈的 马修
God damn it, Matthew.
没事的
It's all right.
我回家立马派一艘船过来接你
I'll send a boat for you the minute we get back.
然后我们回到楠塔基特玩牌 好吗
And we'll play cards back in Nantucket, all right?
好 一言为定 好
- Yeah, it's a deal. - Good.
你要我帮你打开水壶吗
You want me to open that for ya?
我能行的
Naw, I think I'll manage.
上帝保佑你 兄弟
God be with you, Brother.
也保佑你
And you.
彼得森
Brother Peterson?
你一起跟我们走吧 彼得森先生
- Y'all comin' with us? - Mr. Peterson.
和邦德一起登船走吧
Why don't you come on our boat with Mr. Bond.
困住的第48天
在哪儿 他在哪儿
Where... where is he?
波拉德
Pollard.
劳伦斯先生 劳伦斯先生 醒醒
Mr. Lawrence, Mr. Lawrence, wake up.
另一条船去哪儿了
Where has the other boat gone?
波拉德 波拉德 船长波拉德
- Pollard! Pollard! - Captain Pollard!
- Pollard! Pollard! - Cap'n Pollard!
波拉德 船长
- Pollard! - Captain!
波拉德
Pollard!
休息会儿
Get some rest.
本杰明 你在干什么
Benjamin, what are you doing?
他死了
He's dead.
把他丢海里 长官
Throwing him overboard, Sir.
看着我 看着我 本杰明
Look at me, look at me Benjamin.
没有理智的水手会丢弃也许会救自己一命的东西
No right minded sailor discards what might yet save him.
听我说 孩子 听我说
Listen to me, Boy, listen to me.
他能救我们
He can help us.
我的上帝 我们神圣的
My God, our heavenly...
这些生物每日祈盼着食物
Thy creatures wait On Thee for daily food.
决定了
So it was decided.
我们准备了尸体
We prepared the body.
我们去除了内脏
We removed the organs.
分割了他的四肢
Separated his limbs from his body.
从骨头上切下了所有的肉
And cut all the flesh from the bones.
然后
After which...
我们拼起了尸块
we closed body.
然后把尸体缝起来
And then we sewed it up...
尽我们所能
as decently as we could...
然后扔到了海里
and committed it to the sea.
我们先吃了心脏
We ate the heart first.
你有意见
You judge me.
不
No.
那个
There... there...
说完了
it's done.
It is out.
你从未告诉过任何人
You never told anyone?
没有
No.
包括你的妻子
Not even your wife?
你觉得如果她知道我做的罪孽
Do you think she could ever love me,
她还会爱我吗
if she knew the abominations I had committed?
不 她还会爱你的
Yes, she would.
如果你和我相遇的时候告诉我
And if you had told me this story when we met,
我今天还会是你的妻子
I would still wear your ring today.
那个男孩的勇敢
The strength of that boy,
还在你内心
still lives in you.
我看得出
I see that...
即使你自己不觉察
even if you don't.
你可以说完你的故事了 亲爱的
You can finish your story now, My Love.
嘿
Look...
坐起来
Sit up.
听着
Listen.
妈的
Damn thing.
我们还有些水
We still got a few drops of the water left.
别放弃 我们要回家了
Don't ya quit on me, we're goin' home.
你还有家人在吗
Do you have a family...
查斯先生
back home, Mr. Chase?
有的 我的妻子
Yeah, I have wife.
对 还有一个儿子和一个女儿
Yes, and a son or a daughter.
困住的第71天 南美以西1200海里
好
Very well.
船长 我们重新抽签
Cap'n, we'll draw again.
我们不会这么做
We'll do no such thing.
我们重新抽 拉姆斯德尔先生
- We'll draw again. - Mr. Ramsdell,
你要用这枪来指挥
you will assume command of this vessel.
你明白
Ya got that?
你是我们的船长 你的船员需要你
You're our cap'n, your men need you.
船员没事的
The men will be fine.
拜托了 拜托了
Please. Please. Please.
亨利 让我们再抽签
- Henry... - Let us go again.
这是命令
It is an order.
如果你做不到
If you cannot do it,
把枪给其他人
pass the pistol to another man.
我们在赤道无风带几周了
We were weeks in the Doldrums.
太平洋那片区域远比海洋枯竭
That part of the Pacific is more desert than ocean.
太阳炙热
The sun beating down...
我害怕
My fear...
我能想到的是
All I could think about...
所有人都会死而我是最后一个活着的
was that everyone would die and I'd be the last left alive.
查斯只知道我们离陆地还有800英里
Well, as best as Mr. Chase could tell, we were still 800 miles from land.
查斯先生
Mr. Chase.
船长波拉德
Cap'n Pollard.
很高兴见到你
Very happy to see you.
我们生存下来没什么值得高兴
Very little happiness in our survival.
我们也是 长官
Nor in ours, Sir.
巴尔齐莱号
Barzillai?
另一艘船
The third boat?
他们不见了 几天不见了
They're gone, they've been gone for days.
我估计他们迷失了 长官
I'm afraid they're lost, Sir.
查斯先生 你为这个准备好了
Mr. Chase, you are prepared for this.
不过是头白鲸
It's just a whale.
那里 投茅
There! Throw the lance!
投啊
Throw it!
Throw it, drown the lad!
投啊
Throw it!
就是现在 投茅啊
Do it! Now! Throw the lance!
你为什么不投
Why didn't you throw it?
你他妈是个傻子
You're a damn fool.
洋流把我们拆散了
The current drew us apart...
那是我们最后一次见到船长波拉德的鲸船
and that was the last we would see of Captain Pollard's whale boat.
困住的第87天
一艘船
A boat!
前方有一艘船
A boat on the forward bow!
上帝仁慈
May god have mercy.
困住的第90天 1821年2月18日
查斯先生
Mr. Chase.
父亲
Father...
别丢下我 父亲
don't leave me, Father.
嘿 长官
Hey, Sir.
查斯先生 长官 看 看 长官
Mr. Chase. Sir. Look. Look, Sir.
长官
Sir.
看 那里
Look. Out there.
他们来了
They're coming.
他们来救我们了
They're coming for us.
我们在那里被救了
We were rescued there, off the Isle of Mбs Afuera, Chile,
埃塞克斯号沉船90天后
ninety days after the sinking of the Essex.
他们给我们一些衣服和皮革吃
They gave us some old clothes... leathers, too.
起先感觉很难吃
It was hard to eat at first... strange.
他们尽力照顾我们
They looked after us as best they could,
然后他们找到了可以带我们回家的一艘船
then we found a ship that could carry us home.
回家又花了三个月
That voyage took another three months.
1821年6月11日 楠塔基特港口
全岛的人好像都过来看我们回来
It looked like the whole Island turned out to see us return.
但是没有欢呼 只有沉寂
But there were no cheers... only silence.
他们看我们的样子像是看到鬼 幽灵
They looked at us like we were... apparitions... phantoms.
我们没有对任何人说起我们生存的细节
We'd said nothing of the details of our survival to anyone.
但是我猜他们知道我们的困境
But I wondered if they somehow knew of our privations.
也许他们只是好奇
Maybe they were just curious.
我保证过的 不是吗
I promised, didn't I?
天啊
God.
嘿 宝贝 你是谁啊
Hey, Sweetie! Who is this?
菲比安
Phebe Ann.
菲比安·查斯
Phebe Ann Chase.
他是你的父亲
It's your Daddy.
嘿 宝贝
Hey, Sweetie.
他是你的父亲
It's your Daddy.
当然还是有人找上他
Of course they couldn't leave him alone.
查斯先生和他的妻子往家走了不久
Mr. Chase and his wife had scarcely walked a block towards home
他就被拦下来并带回了海事办公室
when he was stopped and made to return to the Maritime Office.
生意上的事还有疑问
There were business matters still in question.
对于这件事
So, to the matter...
因为我们此次航线造成了巨大的人员和财产损失
Due to the significant loss of life and property on our voyage,
将会有一场听证会
it seems there will be an inquiry.
作为船长和大副 我们需要交待事实经过
And, as Captain and first mate, we will be expected to give account of what happened.
是的 当然
Yes, of course.
我就这件事和船主和我父亲讨论过
And, having discussed this with the ship owners and... my father,
显然完全交待经过会有后果
it is clear that full disclosure will have ramifications...
对整个行业有可怕的后果
terrible ramifications for whole industry.
一头白鲸弄沉了埃塞克斯号
That a whale brought down the Essex.
但这是事实
But it's the truth.
如果保险商和投资人开始担心
If the insurance houses and investors were to start worrying about...
海怪把船弄沉
sea monsters sinking ships,
水手们很难活下来
sailors drawing lots to survive...
我们在石油行业 所有人
We are in the oil business... all of us.
在任何一个行业成功的机率一定要比失败的风险要高
And as in any business the probability of success must always be greater the risk incurred.
那么 你有什么建议 乔治
So, what are you suggesting, George?
你就说船搁浅了
That you say that the ship ran aground.
那是个谎言 并且说船员是淹死的
- That's a lie. - And that the men that died drowned.
那也是个谎言
That's another lie.
想想吧 他们会让你当船长
Think on it... they will make you captain.
那个我是有书面保证的
Oh! That pledge I already have in writing.
那个前提是你带回一船的鲸油
Only on the condition you bring home a ship full of oil.
这么做会确保你这件事
This way it's guaranteed.
你会变成有钱人
You would be a wealthy man.
查斯不再是陆人的名字 而是有记录的
The name Chase need no longer be a landsman's name, but an established name
属于楠塔基特岛伟大家族的名字
that belongs among the great families of Nantucket.
你要我为了功名掩盖发生的一切
You want me to whitewash what happened for profit?
我们是要你务实些
We're asking you to be pragmatic.
埃塞克斯号是被一头白鲸撞沉的
The Essex was stoved by a white whale.
我们幸存下来的在装备不良的捕鲸船上
And those of us that survived in ill-equipped whale boats
只能靠犯下罪孽才能存活
had to commit abominations in order to survive.
我们回来后 又被指望传播公然露骨的谎言
And on our return, we're expected to spread barefaced lies,
好让你们这些楠塔基特岛岛船主们
so that you, the ship owners of Nantucket,
赚钱晚上再睡得安稳觉吗
might line your pockets and sleep well at night?
我不会掩盖真相
Well, I will not embroil the truth.
乔治 你也不应该
Nor should you, George.
我最后一次见他
That last time I saw him...
查斯先生 长官
Mr. Chase, Sir.
我说不出我想说的话
I couldn't find the right words to say what I wanted.
汤姆斯
Thomas.
也许我没什么想说的
Perhaps there ARE no words.
我 我要去法尔茅斯了
I'm... I'm gonna be on my way to Falmouth, and...
那个
it's...
那个 很荣幸 长官
it's... it's been an honor, Sir,
能够服务于您
to serve with you.
是我的荣幸 尼克森先生
The honor has been mine, Mr. Nickerson.
拿着
Take it.
祝你好运 汤姆斯
Good luck out there, Thomas.
谢谢 长官
Thank you, Sir.
第二天乔治·波拉德被召唤到听证会
Next day George Pollard was called before the inquiry.
先生们 船长乔治·波拉德
Gentlemen, Captain George Pollard.
楠塔基特所有重要人物都在那儿
All the important men of Nantucket were there...
这是惯例
it was a formality.
日安 船长 请坐
Good day to you, Captain, please sit down.
事实是
For the record then.
埃塞克斯号是在厄瓜多尔以西被一头1200多米长的白鲸撞沉的
The Essex was stoved by a white whale 12 hundred meters west of Ecuador.
就像欧文·查斯说的那样
It was as if Owen Chase himself had spoken.
他告诉了他们真相
He told them the truth.
船长波拉德的良心发现了
Cap'n Pollard's conscience was clear...
但那场听证会是个耻辱
but the inquiry was a sham.
至于那头白鲸 他们再也没有找到
over the white whale... they never found it.
他再一次出航但在夏威夷搁浅
He ran a second ship aground off of Hawaii...
两次诅咒
twice cursed.
再也没有出航过
Never sailed again.
欧文·查斯
And Owen Chase?
他说到做到
He was a man of his word.
他派了一艘船去了杜斯特岛
First, he sent a boat back to Ducie Island.
花花公子已经死了
Mr. Joy had passed...
但是其他人居然还都活着
but the other three were incredibly still alive.
然后呢
And then?
他带着家人搬到了新贝德福德
Then he packed up his family and moved to New Bedford...
去重新开始生活
to start over...
在一家商店
in a merchant...
完成自己的人生旅程
sailing his own terms.
你用钱换到故事了 梅尔维尔先生
Well, you certainly got your money's worth, Mr. Melville.
这二月的夜晚真是一年中最漫长的
These February nights are the longest of the year.
你们都可以休息了 我不行
- Well, you can both rest now. - Leave me...
我还有一段时间不能休息
I shall not be resting for some time.
为什么
Why?
你得到了你的故事 情节都有了
Ya got your story there, and your plot is all there.
也许我想要的不是情节
Maybe it wasn't a plot I was after.
不是 那是什么
No, what then?
你今晚给我的其他东西
Something else you've given me tonight.
是什么
What is that?
敢于去别人不敢去的地方的勇气
The courage to go where... one does not want to go.
梅尔维尔先生
Mr. Melville,
你听到的 我告诉你的
what you've heard, what I've told you,
是否都会成为你书中的一部分
will it all be of service to your book?
这会是部虚构的小说 尼克森先生
It will be a work of fiction, Mr. Nickerson,
受真实事件启发
inspired by truth,
但我不觉得我会用全部事实
but I don't believe I'll feel the need to use all of it.
谢谢 给
- Thank you. - Here...
拿着这个
take that with you.
不 钱是给你的 我坚持
No, the money is for you, I insist.
我坚持你要收下
I insist you keep it.
我坚持这谈话里还是有一个人是清醒的
And I insist that one person in this conversation is sober.
该回马萨诸塞州皮茨菲尔德了
So, it's back to Pittsfield, Massachusetts.
祝你好运
Well, good luck.
谢谢
Thank you.
你知道吗
Ya know...
我听说宾夕法尼亚州一个人最近在地上钻了一个洞
I heard a man from Pennsylvania drilled a hole in the ground recently,
发现了油
and found oil.
不会是真的吧
That can't be true.
我也听说过
I heard it, too.
地上的油
Oil from ground.
真想不到
Fancy that.
赫尔曼·梅尔维尔 1850年完成了他的小说
一年后白鲸记发表
对于白鲸记纳撒尼尔·霍桑盛赞它会成为美国伟大的作品